Matt Harrell

Front-End Web Developer

Portfolio: <u>matt-harrell.dev</u> GitHub:<u>github.com/matt-harrell</u>

Phone: 910-833-2451

Email: matthew.h.harrell@gmail.com
LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/matthharrell
PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Meticulous Web Developer holding a Master of Arts in Interactive Media with over two years of experience in providing high-caliber coding solutions, web development, and executing software development lifecycle. Highly knowledgeable in React, JavaScript, CSS, and HTML, and leveraging those technologies to solve problems.

EXPERIENCE

Covetrus | Front-End Web Developer | Remote | July 2021 - Present

- Designed and executed innovative coding solutions by utilizing HTML, CSS, and JavaScript which resulted in increased operational efficiency that led to a promotion as Front-end Developer
- Mentored fellow developers on new technologies with the creation of documentation and training sessions that enabled them to solve more complex problems
- Customized templates from Content Management Systems (CMS) such as WordPress to achieve marketing conversion goals
- Assessed code from other developers to make sure that it covered all of Covetrus use cases which led to a more optimized user experience across Covetrus domains
- Collaborated with Designers, Products Managers, and Project Managers on multiple projects through instant messages and meetings to create creative technological solutions

Freelance Web Developer | Remote | May 2021 - July 2021

- Built websites for small organizations using WordPress to enhance business online presence.
- Partnered with other freelancers to create designs to modernize organizations existing websites to help the business achieve their desired outcome
- Corresponded with clients to understand their particular needs and then create a customized solution that would meet their need

Heartoscope | Internship - Web Developer April 2021 - May 2021

- Created a website for a non-profit using WordPress that centralized its online presence and was a platform to acquire new volunteers
- Collaborated with designers and content strategists to deliver a web experience that simplified the non-profits communication process
- Devised tutorials and documentation for the non-profit to enable them to update and maintain their websites after the internship ended

SOFT SKILLS

Interpersonal communication, Problem Solviing, Adaptability, Collaboration, Leadership

TECHNICAL SKILLS

React, JavaScript, TypeScript, CSS, HTML, Git, WordPress, Figma

EDUCATION

Master of Arts in Interactive Media, Elon University, May 2021
Bachelor of Arts in Communication Studies, Campbell University, May 2019
CERTIFICATIONS

Certificate in Front-End Engineering, Codecademy, March 11, 2023